A Guide to the Dr. Richard Zallen Papers, 1957-2009
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Dr. Richard Zallen Papers, 1957-2009
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2008-069
36 boxes; 17.4 cu. ft.
The Dr. Richard Zallen Papers document the research and professional development of a physics professor at Virginia Tech specializing in condensed matter research. Papers largely cover the second half of the twentieth century and include information on research at Xerox; professional correspondence; Virginia Tech lecture notes; drafts of published work; and documents concerning trips, sabbaticals, and conferences. Materials include hand-written documents, published material, flat plate drawings, photographs, a sample of melt-spun amorphous, and stamps from various countries.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The Dr. Richard Zallen Papers were donated to Special Collections in 2007.
Biographical Information
Richard Henry Zallen was born in New York City in 1937. After receiving his bachelors of science in physics from Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute in 1957, Zallen continued his education at Harvard University‐eventually receiving his Ph.D. in Applied Physics in 1964. From 1966 to 1983, Dr. Zallen worked at the Xerox Research Laboratories in Rochester, New York. While working at Xerox, he was part of a team that patented Spin Coated Photoconductor Films. After his research at Xerox, Dr. Zallen served as a professor of physics at Virginia Tech. In 1976 Dr. Zallen became a fellow of the American Physical Society. During his sabbaticals, Dr. Zallen held several visiting appointments. From 1971 to 1972 he acted as the visiting associate professor of physics at the Technion, The Israel Institute of Technology, in Haifa; in the summer of 1979 he was the visiting professor at the Université de Paris VI; from 1990 to 1991 he was the SERC senior research fellow at Imperial College in London; and in 1998 he served as the visiting professor at Imperial College in London. Dr. Zallen's primary research interest lies in experimental studies of the optical properties of solids. In pursuance of his interests, Dr. Zallen has published more than one hundred articles and a widely cited book, The Physics of Amorphous Solids. In 2006, the Virginia Tech Board of Visitors honored Dr. Zallen with the title professor emeritus.
Scope and Content
The Dr. Richard Zallen Papers document the research and professional development of a physics professor at Virginia Tech, specializing in condensed matter research, largely during the second half of the twentieth century. The papers include information concerning Zallen's study at Harvard and his work at Xerox; research notes; professional correspondence; Virginia Tech lectures; drafts of published works; and materials concerning trips, sabbaticals, and conferences. The corporate and governmental institutions with which Zallen worked include: the Office of Naval Research, Raytheon Manufacturing Company, Texas Instruments, and IBM. Examples of mentioned geographical locations are Israel, Belgium, China, England, France, Canada, Italy, and a host of cities in the United States. Materials include hand-written documents, published material, flat plate drawings, photographs, a sample of melt-spun amorphous, and stamps from various countries. Expanatory notes made by Zallen in 2006 annotate many documents. Some significant documents include supporting patent materials for Spin Coated Photoconductor Films, letters concerning the protest by industrial scientists at Xerox over the escalation of the war in Indo-China, and copies of APS Solid State Correspondence discussing the formation of Solid-State Physics.
(NOTE: Many of the folders in this collection contain two sets of dates. Dates within parentheses designate the date originally provided by the creator and usually indicate when an event/research occurred. Dates outside of parentheses indicate the chronological range of materials found within the collection. )
Arrangement
The collection maintains original order. Papers are organized by topic and generally appear in reverse chronological order. Correspondence appears alphabetically.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Zallen, Richard. The Physics of Amorphous Solids. New York: Wiley, c1983
In Spec Storage: QC176.8.A44 Z34 1983 c.3
Contents List
- Series I: Xerox
  - Xerox PhD Recruiting (1 of 2), 1982-1983 (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Xerox PhD Recruiting (2 of 2), 1982-1983 (Box-folder 1:2)
  - Xerox to VT: Ritsko Electron Apparatus Eels (Summer 1985), 1983-1990 (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Xerox to VT: Opt. Spectrometer, Fall 1983 (Box-folder 1:4)
  - Speakers Hosted at Xerox [mostly], 1970-1989 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Diamond-Anvil Cell (Xerox), 1973-1980 (Box-folder 1:6)
  - Staff Presentation (Xerox), Dec 1981 (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Staff Presentation / Project Review, Dec 14, 1981 (Box-folder 1:8)
  - Patent for Spin Coated Photoconductor Films, 1977-1989 (Box-folder 1:9)
  - Xerox Advisers' Reports: Bardeen, Tribus, Scheraga, 1979 (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Xerox Research Plans, 1968-1982 (Box-folder 1:11)
  - Xerox Monthly Highlights and Quarterly Reports, 1976-1983 (Box-folder 1:12)
  - Xerox R & D Book, 1976 (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Xerox Capital Equipment, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 1:14)
  - Xerox Trip Reports (1 of 2), 1966-1982 (Box-folder 1:15)
  - Xerox Trip Reports (2 of 2), 1966-1982 (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Xerox Lab and Office Layout, 1965, 1983 (Box-folder 2:2)
  - Xerox Research Labs, plus...(1 of 2), 1965-2002 (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Xerox Research Labs, plus...(2 of 2), 1965-2002 (Box-folder 2:4)
  - APS Fellow, 1976 (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Essay on Electrostatics in Xerography, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 2:6)
  - Computation Notebook 2/4, 1969-1971; 1984-1997 (Box-folder 2:7)
  - Computation Notebook 3, 1975-1984 (Box-folder 2:8)
  - Computation Notebook 1, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 2:9)
  - Perkin Elmer 16 U / Lab Setup at Xerox, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 2:10)
  - Xerox, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 2:11)
- Series II: Harvard Years
  - Effect of Pressure of R (h 2) of Ag and Cu, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - The Effect of Pressure on Optical Properties of Semiconductors, 1964 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - Thesis, 1964 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - MacLeod on Beeswax, Optical Sample Preparation, 1966 (Box-folder 3:4)
  - Reflectivity of Ge, InAs, GaSb, 1962-1965 (Box-folder 3:5)
  - Reflectivity of Silicon vs. Hydrostatic Pressure, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 3:6)
  - GaP paper, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 3:7)
  - RZ thesis notes with comment / WP Comments, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 3:8)
  - Calculations for GaP Absorption Edge under Pressure, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 3:9)
  - GaP data, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 3:10)
  - Stimulated Emission in Gallium Arsenide (1 of 2), 1962-1963 (Box-folder 3:11)
  - Stimulated Emission in Gallium Arsenide (2 of 2), 1962-1963 (Box-folder 3:12)
  - Notes on Optical Properties of Solids, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 3:13)
    Includes notes on the quantum theory of radiation and absorption edges and a photo from the Technion.
  - Harvard Work on Absorption Edges, 1961 (Box-folder 3:14)
  - Harvard University Laboratory Notebook Physics 1, Section 6, 1965 (Box-folder 3:15)
  - Harvard University Laboratory Notebook Physics 1, Section 5, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 4:1)
  - Harvard University Laboratory Notebook Physics 1, Section 4, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 4:2)
  - Harvard University Laboratory Notebook Physics 1, Section 3, 1961 (Box-folder 4:3)
  - Harvard University Laboratory Notebook, Section 2, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 4:4)
  - Harvard University Laboratory Notebook Physics 1, Section 1, 1960 (Box-folder 4:5)
    Includes charts and diagrams.
- Series III: Raytheon Manufacturing Company
  - Raytheon (1958-1959), 1959-1960 (Box-folder 4:6)
    Includes Technical Memorandum T-189 of Sep 17 1959, Measurement and Interpretation of Absorption Spectra of Solids in the Absorption Edge Region of Dec 15 1960 by D. M. Warschauer and Electroluminescence under Pulsed Square Wave Excitation by R. Zallen, V. T. Eriksen, and H. Ahlburg.
  - Raytheon Manufacturing Company-Engineering Notebook, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 5:1)
- Series IV: Virginia Tech
  - RZ Funding Notes at VT / Excerpts; ITT / Texas Instruments / CIT / Philip Morris, 1985-1996 (Box-folder 5:2)
  - VT Physics Site Visit / Presentation to Armstrong Committee, 1996 (Box-folder 5:3)
  - VT Activities Reports (1 of 2), 1986-2004 (Box-folder 5:4)
  - VT Activities Reports (2 of 2), 1986-2004 (Box-folder 5:5)
  - Lecture Pictures / Exams (1 of 2), 1989-2006; 1947 (Box-folder 5:6)
  - Lecture Pictures / Exams (2 of 2), 1989-2006; 1947 (Box-folder 5:7)
  - Miscellaneous Teaching, 1983-2006 (Box-folder 5:8)
  - RZ VT Colloquium, April 1990 (Box-folder 5:9)
  - RZ Hosted VT Speakers [including RZ], 1983-2003 (Box-folder 5:10)
  - Department Demographics, 1988 (Box-folder 5:11)
  - RZ Part of VT Proposal to IBM, c. 1986 (Box-folder 5:12)
  - PhD and MS Students, 1994-2004 (Box-folder 5:13)
  - VT Lab Setup, 1983-1989 (Box-folder 5:14)
  - VT Memos (1 of 2), 1983-2000 (Box-folder 5:15)
  - VT Memos (2 of 2), 1983-2000 (Box-folder 6:1)
  - VT Lab Photos, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 6:2)
  - Xerox to Virginia Tech, 1983-2007 (Box-folder 6:3)
- Series V: Isakson Prize
  - 1984 Isakson Prize Committee, winner Manuel Cardona, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 6:4)
  - 1982 Isakson Prize Committee, winner Jan Tauc, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 7:1)
- Series VI: Documented Talks
  - Percolation Theory: A Model for All Seasons, 1983 (Box-folder 7:2)
    Includes one VHS tape and one CD.
  - Michel Besson's Presentation on High Pressure, c. 1979 (Box-folder 7:3)
    On videocassette.
  - Michel Besson's Presentation on High Pressure of 1979, 2006 (Box-folder 7:4)
- Series VII: Meetings, Trips, Talks, and Sabbaticals
  - Los Angeles (Mar 2005), 2005 (Box-folder 7:5)
  - Saint Adele [Thorpefest], Montreal, and Cambridge (Aug 2004), 2004 (Box-folder 8:1)
  - Montreal (Mar 2004), 2004 (Box-folder 8:2)
  - Besson Colloquium Paris (May 16 2003), 1980-2004 (Box-folder 8:3)
  - Michigan State (Spring 2003), 2002-2003 (Box-folder 8:4)
  - Austin, Texas (Mar 2003), 2003 (Box-folder 8:5)
  - High Pressure Semiconductor Physics Conference [WP et al.], London (Aug 2002), 2000-2002 (Box-folder 8:6)
  - RPI Reunion, Troy and Rochester, New York (Jun 2002), 2002 (Box-folder 8:7)
  - Indianapolis (Mar 2002), 2001-2002 (Box-folder 8:8)
  - Lubbock, Texas (Apr 2001), 1997-2001 (Box-folder 8:9)
  - Seattle (Mar 2001), 2000-2001 (Box-folder 8:10)
  - Cincinnati (Nov 2000), 1988-2000 (Reel 8:11)
  - Nano Conference at VT and Physics Colloquium (Nov 2000), 2000 (Box-folder 8:12)
  - Cambridge / London, UK (Jul 2000), 2000 (Box-folder 8:13)
  - March Meeting of the American Physical Society, Minneapolis (2000), 2000 (Box-folder 8:14)
  - Raleigh (Feb 2000), 2000 (Box-folder 8:15)
  - London / Israel (Jul / Aug, Summer 1999), 1998-1999 (Box-folder 8:16)
  - March Meeting Atlanta (1999), 1998-1999 (Box-folder 8:17)
  - Haifa / Oren's Memorial Symposium (Jan 1999), 1998-1999 (Box-folder 8:18)
  - Dow TAB meeting at MIT (Oct 2, 1998), 1998-1999 (Box-folder 8:19)
  - Imperial College, London, (Jan-Aug, 1998), 1997-1999 (Box-folder 9:1)
  - Cincinnati (Jun 6, 1997), 1997 (Box-folder 9:2)
  - Travel Arrangements for Quantum Epitaxial Designs, Inc. Discussion, (Sep 20, 1996), 1996 (Box-folder 9:3)
  - NATO Advanced Study Institute, Sozopol [Black Sea] (May-Jun, 199), 1996-1997 (Box-folder 9:4)
  - List of Trips / Talks / Sabbaticals (1996-1984), 2006 (Box-folder 9:5)
  - St. Louis / APS (Mar 1996), 1996 (Box-folder 9:6)
  - Richmond Conference (Nov 1995), 1994-1997 (Box-folder 9:7)
  - NSF IMR Panel (Feb 1, 1995), 1994-1995 (Box-folder 9:8)
  - Oak Ridge Workshop (Oct 1994), 1994 (Box-folder 9:9)
  - Vancouver / 22nd ICPS (Aug 15-19, 1994), 1994 (Box-folder 9:10)
  - FLG Symposium, Colorado (Aug 7-11, 1994), 1993-1994 (Box-folder 9:11)
  - ECD (May 1994), 1986-1994 (Box-folder 9:12)
  - New Alliances for Economic Development, Charlottesville (May 1994), 1994 (Box-folder 9:13)
  - Pittsburgh (Mar 1994), 1994 (Box-folder 9:14)
  - Nanoscale Workshop, College Park, Maryland (October 1993), 1993 (Box-folder 9:15)
  - Oxford (May 21 1993), 1993 (Box-folder 9:16)
  - NEC, Princeton (Sep 1992), 1992 (Box-folder 10:1)
  - March Meeting, Indianapolis (1992), 1991-1992 (Box-folder 10:2)
  - Clusters, Richmond (Oct 19), 1991-1993 (Box-folder 10:3)
  - Cambridge, UK (Aug 1991), 1991 (Box-folder 10:4)
  - Leicester / Surrey (May 1991), 1991-1994 (Box-folder 10:5)
  - Imperial College (Sep 1990-Aug 1991), 1989-1995 (Box-folder 10:6)
  - Exeter (Apr 1991), 1991 (Box-folder 10:7)
  - University of Reading (Jan 1991), 1990-1991 (Box-folder 10:8)
  - Philip Morris R&D Center (notes from Sep 6 1989; Jul 6 1990), 1989-1990 (Box-folder 10:9)
  - VPI Physics Colloquium (Apr 12 1990), 1990 (Box-folder 10:10)
  - March Meeting, Anaheim (1990), 1990 (Box-folder 10:11)
  - University of Paris; Imperial College (Oct 1989), 1989 (Box-folder 10:12)
  - Asheville (Aug / Sep 1989), 1989-1990 (Box-folder 10:13)
  - Xerox WRC (Jun 27 1989), 1989 (Box-folder 10:14)
  - Richard Zallen and Calvin Doss's Talks with Philip Morris (Jun 22 1989), 1989 (Box-folder 10:15)
  - Penn State (Jun 1 1989), 1988-1992 (Box-folder 10:16)
  - Dow Chemical (Apr 28 1989), 1986-1995 (Box-folder 10:17)
  - Wake Forest (Apr 13 1989), 1986-1989 (Box-folder 10:18)
  - APS March Meeting, St. Louis, 1989 (Box-folder 10:19)
  - MRX & Lincoln Lab, Boston (Nov 27-Dec 3 1988), 1988 (Box-folder 11:1)
  - Penn State (Oct 18 1988), 1988 (Box-folder 11:2)
  - University of Cincinnati (Nov 9 1988), 1988 (Box-folder 11:3)
  - CIT Superconductivity Workshop / Philip Morris Research Center, Richmond (May 18-21 1988), 1988 (Box-folder 11:4)
  - SUNY Buffalo (April 21 1988), 1988 (Box-folder 11:5)
  - March Meeting, New Orleans (1988), 1988-1989 (Box-folder 11:6)
  - Texas Instruments, Dallas (Feb 11 1988), 1988 (Box-folder 11:7)
  - Philip Morris Research Center (Nov 23 1987), 1987 (Box-folder 11:8)
  - Kodak / Exxon (MCH) (Sep 9-11 1987), 1987 (Box-folder 11:9)
  - Gordon Conference on ionomers, (Aug 4-7 1987), 1987 (Box-folder 11:10)
  - Erice (Jun 1987), 1977-2002 (Box-folder 11:11)
  - UNC / Marvin Silver (Apr 7 1987), 1986-1987 (Box-folder 11:12)
  - New York, New York (Mar 1987), 1987 (Box-folder 11:13)
  - Texas Instruments Trip, Dallas (Mar 5-8 1987), 1987 (Box-folder 11:14)
  - BIAA Sh. Inst. Ceramics, China (Jul 1986), 1986 (Box-folder 11:15)
    [see correspondence for Ai-Lien Juno]
  - ECD [Energy Conversion Devices] Trip (May 21 1986), 1986 (Box-folder 11:16)
  - Penn / Illinois (May 1-2 1986), 1985-1990 (Box-folder 11:17)
  - Las Vegas Meeting / WP-Schrift (Mar 31 1986), 1986 (Box-folder 11:18)
  - Texas A&M (Mar 23-26 1986), 1985-1987 (Box-folder 11:19)
  - Brown MRL / Harvard Seminar (Feb 1986), 1985-1986 (Box-folder 12:1)
  - Texas Instruments, Dallas (Jan 31 1986), 1985-1986 (Box-folder 12:2)
  - Vanderbilt / Bob Weeks (Oct 21 1985), 1985-1992 (Box-folder 12:3)
  - Conference on Structure, Bloomfield Hills [IαS] (Jun 3-6 1985), 1984-1985 (Box-folder 12:4)
  - EPRI Workshop, San Diego (May 12-17 1985), 1984-1985 (Box-folder 12:5)
  - NY State Section Meeting, Corning, New York (Apr 1985), 1984-1985 (Box-folder 12:6)
  - March Meeting, Baltimore, 1985 (Box-folder 12:7)
  - Case Western Reserve, Southern Ohio / Johns Hopkins (Mar 19-21 1985), 1984-1985 (Box-folder 12:8)
  - UVA (Feb 8 1985), 1984-1985 (Box-folder 12:9)
  - Cincinnati (Nov 1984), 1984-1988 (Box-folder 12:10)
  - Nashville (Jul 1984), 1984 (Box-folder 12:11)
  - March Meeting, Detroit (1984), 1984 (Box-folder 12:12)
  - DuPont (Mar 20 1984), 1984 (Box-folder 12:13)
  - University of Pennsylvania (Feb 17 1984), 1983-1984 (Box-folder 12:14)
  - 1960-1984 Meetings, Trips, Talks, Sabbaticals List, 1994-2006 (Box-folder 12:15)
  - IAS [ECD] Short Course / Amorphous Semiconductors, Bloomfield Hills, Michigan (May 18 1984), 1983-1984 (Box-folder 12:16)
  - University of Maryland (Apr 24 1984), 1983-1984 (Box-folder 12:17)
  - ECD / IAS / UM / MSU (Nov 1983), 1983-1984 (Box-folder 12:18)
  - NC State (Oct 3 1983), 1981-1983 (Box-folder 12:19)
  - SPEX (Sep 22 1983), 1983-1984 (Box-folder 12:20)
  - Penn State (Sep 15 1983), 1983 (Box-folder 12:21)
  - Schlumberger (Jul 11 1983), 1983 (Box-folder 12:22)
  - Symposium on Noncrystaline Solids, Reston, Virginia (May 1983), 1983 (Box-folder 12:23)
  - March Meeting, Los Angeles (1983), 1983 (Box-folder 12:24)
  - RPI talk (Oct 20 1982), 1982 (Box-folder 12:25)
  - Visit to Penn (Apr 1982), 1977-1983 (Box-folder 12:26)
  - Dallas Trip, UT‐Austin / VT‐Dallas / Xerox Committee (Apr 1982), 1982 (Box-folder 13:1)
  - March Meeting, Dallas (1982), 1981-1982 (Box-folder 13:2)
  - Brown, CUNY, APS / DCMP (Nov, Dec 1981), 1981-1982 (Box-folder 13:3)
  - Amorphous Conferences, Grenoble (Jul 1981), 1981 (Box-folder 13:4)
  - Phoenix, Houston, Tuscan (Mar 1981), 1980-1988 (Box-folder 13:5)
  - HU / BU / GTE (Feb 1981), 1980-1983 (Box-folder 13:6)
  - Aspen (1980), 1980-1990 (Box-folder 13:7)
  - In this Box, 2006 (Box-folder 13:8)
  - March Meeting, New York, New York (Mar 1980), 1979-1980 (Box-folder 13:9)
  - 8th International Conference on Amorphous and Liquid Semiconductors, Cambridge, Massachusetts, (Aug 1979), 1979 (Box-folder 13:10)
  - University of Paris, Place Jussieu (Jun / Jul 1979), 1979-1995 (Box-folder 13:11)
  - Bell Labs / Exxon / NRL / Brooklyn College / NRL, New York, New Jersey (May 1979), 1979-1982 (Box-folder 13:12)
  - March Meeting, Chicago (1979), 1979 (Box-folder 13:13)
  - Visit to McMaster / Jim Morrison (Nov 28-29 1978), 1975-1979 (Box-folder 13:14)
  - Semiconductor Conference, Edinburgh (1978), 1977-1978 (Box-folder 13:15)
  - March Meeting, Washington / Conference at IBM, Yorktown Heights/Rutgers (1978), 1978 (Box-folder 13:16)
  - APS Invited Talk, Miami (Nov 1977), 1977 (Box-folder 13:17)
  - Statistical Physics 13, Haifa (Aug 1977), 1977 (Box-folder 14:1)
  - Gordon Conference on Molecular Solids, Plymouth, New Hampshire (Jun 1977) 1976-1977 (Box-folder 14:2)
  - RZ WRC Colloquium (May 18, 1977), 1977 (Box-folder 14:3)
  - Penn (Apr 1977), 1977-1982 (Box-folder 14:4)
  - March Meeting, San Diego (1977), 1977 (Box-folder 14:5)
  - RPI (Nov 10, 1976), 1976 (Box-folder 14:6)
  - Elliot W. Montroll's Birthday Party at the University of Rochester (Nov 4 1976), 1976 (Box-folder 14:7)
  - Penn State (Sep 1976), 1976 (Box-folder 14:8)
  - Aspen (Aug 1976), 1976 (Box-folder 14:9)
  - MIT (Apr 23, 1976), 1976 (Box-folder 14:10)
  - March Meeting, Atlanta / Williamsburg (1976), 1976 (Box-folder 14:11)
  - Gordon Conference on 2DSolids, Plymouth, New Hampshire (Jul 1975), 1975-1977 (Box-folder 14:12)
  - PbI2 / APS March Meeting, Denver (Mar 1975), 1975 (Box-folder 14:13)
  - Bat Sheva Seminar, Haifa (Jan 1975), 1972-1975 (Box-folder 14:14)
  - Figures for VUE-Graphs, Haifa (Jan 1975), 1974 (Box-folder 14:15)
  - University of Chicago Visit (Oct 1974), 1974 (Box-folder 14:16)
  - Semiconductor Conference, Stuttgart, Federal Republic of Germany (Jul 1974), 1974 (Box-folder 14:17)
  - Lab Visits / Correspondence: Lausanne, Zurich, Stuttgart (Jul 1974), 1974 (Box-folder 14:18)
  - NRL Seminar (May 1974), 1974 (Box-folder 14:19)
  - Conference on Tetrahedrally-Bonded Amorphous Semiconductors, Yorktown Heights / March Meeting, Philadelphia 1973-1974 (Box-folder 14:20)
  - Phase Transition Conference, State College, Pennsylvania (May 1973), 1973 (Box-folder 15:1)
  - 1973 Talk at Palo Alto Research Center / March Meeting, San Diego (Mar 1973), 1973 (Box-folder 15:2)
  - Talk on Optical Properties at Amorphous and Molecular Solids, Xerox Webster Research Center (Mar 1973), 1973 (Box-folder 15:3)
  - Xerox Percolation Talk (Jan 1973), 1973 (Box-folder 15:4)
  - Varenna (Jul 1972), 1972-1975 (Box-folder 15:5)
  - Technion (1 of 2) (1971-1972), 1970-1972 (Box-folder 15:6)
    Some documents are in Hebrew.
  - Technion (2 of 2) (1971-1972), 1970-1972 (Box-folder 15:7)
  - March Meeting, Cleveland (1971), 1971 (Box-folder 15:8)
  - Brown (Nov 1970), 1970 (Box-folder 15:9)
  - Solid State Talk [NAS SSSP], Rochester (Nov 4 1970), 1970 (Box-folder 15:10)
  - University of Rochester Talk (Oct 1970), 1970 (Box-folder 15:11)
  - Semiconductor Conference [1970 Boston Conference] (Aug 1970), 1970 (Box-folder 15:12)
  - Washington Lobbying Trip, 1970 (Box-folder 15:13)
  - IBM Physics Colloquium [Jim McGrody] (Apr 30 1970), 1970 (Box-folder 15:14)
  - March Meeting, Dallas (1970), 1970 (Box-folder 15:15)
  - APS New York (Feb 1969), 1969 (Box-folder 15:16)
  - Gordon Conference on Disordered Systems, Meridian, New Hampshire (Aug 1968), 1968 (Box-folder 15:17)
  - Moscow / Prague / Cambridge, UK (Jul-Aug 1968), 1968-1969 (Box-folder 15:18)
  - March Meeting, Chicago, 1967 (Box-folder 16:1)
  - APS, New York, 1967 (Box-folder 16:2)
  - March Meeting at Duke, 1966 (Box-folder 16:3)
  - Conference on the Optical Properties of Metals, Paris (1965), 1965-1966 (Box-folder 16:4)
  - March Meeting, Kansas City, 1965 (Box-folder 16:5)
  - APS, New York (Jan 1964), 1964 (Box-folder 16:6)
  - NATO Summer School on Optical Properties, Ghent, Belgium (Jul 1962), 1962-2007 (Box-folder 16:7)
  - RZ's First APS March Meeting, Baltimore (Mar 1962), 1962 (Box-folder 16:8)
  - APS, New York (Jan 1960), 1960 (Box-folder 16:9)
- Series XIII: Correspondence
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1971-1990 (Box-folder 16:10)
  - Technion Correspondence (1 of 2), 1971-1997 (Box-folder 16:11)
  - Technion Correspondence (2 of 2), 1971-1997 (Box-folder 16:12)
  - Hebrew University, Tel-Aviv Correspondence, 1974-1992 (Box-folder 16:13)
  - Marty Abkowitz, 1973-2002 (Box-folder 16:14)
  - Dave Adler (1 of 2), 1958-2001 (Box-folder 17:1)
  - Dave Adler (2 of 2), 1958-2001 (Box-folder 17:2)
  - Hayo Ahlburg, 1959-1989 (Box-folder 17:3)
  - Phil Anderson, 1974-1996 (Box-folder 17:4)
  - Mark Azbel, 1977 (Box-folder 17:5)
  - George Bauer, 1970-1974 (Box-folder 17:6)
  - Michel Besson (1 of 2), 1965-2004 (Box-folder 17:7)
  - Michel Besson (2 of 2), 1965-2004 (Box-folder 17:7)
  - Punit Boolchand, 1984-2001 (Box-folder 17:9)
  - Tutu Bose, 1986-1997 (Box-folder 17:10)
  - Oren Brafman (1 of 3), 1970-1999 (Box-folder 17:11)
  - Oren Brafman (2 of 3), 1970-1999 (Box-folder 18:1)
  - Oren Brafman (3 of 3), 1970-1999 (Box-folder 18:2)
  - Bridgman, 1961-2002 (Box-folder 18:3)
  - Brodsky, 1970-1983 (Box-folder 18:4)
  - Eli Burstein, 1970-1994 (Box-folder 18:5)
  - Larry Burton, 1984-1994 (Box-folder 18:6)
  - Cardona, 1959-2005 (Box-folder 18:7)
  - Cazaux, 1973 (Box-folder 18:8)
  - Arthur C. Clarke, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 18:9)
  - Marvin Cohen, 1980-1994 (Box-folder 18:10)
  - Morrel Cohen, 1964-1997 (Box-folder 18:11)
  - Esther Conwell, 1973-2003 (Box-folder 18:12)
    Includes historic letters about the formation of the Division of Solid-State Physics.
  - Coxeter, 1958-1985 (Box-folder 18:13)
  - Ted Davis, 1979-2000 (Box-folder 18:14)
  - de Gennes, 1976-1991 (Box-folder 18:15)
  - John de Neufville, 1979- 2006 (Box-folder 19:1)
  - Calvin Doss, 1988-2002 (Box-folder 19:2)
  - Walter Duncan / Texas Instruments, 1987-1999 (Box-folder 19:3)
  - Leo Falicov, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 19:4)
  - Jeff Feng, 1982-2006 (Box-folder 19:5)
  - Paul Flory, 1982 (Box-folder 19:6)
  - Alan Fowler, 1970-1995 (Box-folder 19:7)
  - Peter Franken, 1963 (Box-folder 19:8)
  - Hellmut Fritzsche, 1972-1987 (Box-folder 19:9)
  - Frank Galeener, 1973-1995 (Box-folder 19:10)
  - Art Geissberger, 1984-2000 (Box-folder 19:11)
  - Marty Glicksman / Rensselaer, 1976-2007 (Box-folder 19:12)
  - Rey Gonzalez, 1987-2006 (Box-folder 19:13)
  - Paul Grant, 1967-2006 (Box-folder 19:14)